[Kurapika] To verify, are you Pakunoda
of the Phantom Troupe?
Yes, I am.
She's telling the truth.
Let's begin.
I will present each of you
with two conditions.
If you choose to abide by them,
I will release your leader.
[Chrollo] Figure it out, Pakunoda.
He's more concerned about his friends
than killing me to satisfy his revenge.
That is the chain user's weakness!
[theme music playing]
SIGNAL x TO x RETREAT
[Kurapika] I’ll start with the conditions
for the leader.
First, I hereby forbid
all further use of Nen.
[breathing shakily]
Is this really the right move?
If I eliminate the boss,
the Spider will fall apart.
That was the idea, but...
I have absolutely no value as a hostage.
Everything that he’s saying
right now is true.
[Kurapika] But the Spider can live on,
even without a head.
The leader isn't everything.
The group would be more than willing
to sacrifice him
if they felt it necessary.
That is the nature of the Phantom Troupe.
I can cut off the head,
but it’s no guarantee the spider will die.
The question is,
is there any other alternative?
Is there some kind of miracle
that can get me out of this bind?
[sighs] There isn't.
None that I can think of.
Yes, this is right.
In this moment, this is what I have to do.
I must get those two back.
That is my top priority!
I’ve lost too many people already.
I will not lose my friends!
Second, I forbid all contact
with other Troupe members from now on.
Those are my conditions.
And to make certain you adhere to them,
I will stab your leader
with my Judgment Chain:
Arbiter Little Finger.
It’s up to you now, Pakunoda.
Are these conditions acceptable?
Yes, I accept.
[Kurapika] Pakunoda, you're next.
First off, release Gon and Killua,
uninjured, before midnight,
and without any deceptions.
Second, you are also forbidden
to reveal anything about me.
Accept and I’ll stab you
with the chain as well.
Yes, go ahead.
-[chain rattling]
-[grunts]
Hey, if Gon and Killua
were being controlled by a Manipulator,
could you tell from their heartbeats?
[Melody] Maybe.
I've met Killua before,
so I know his normal heartbeat.
I should be able to tell
if anything has changed.
Good enough.
Before the exchange,
I have something to say.
[heart beating]
[Melody] Kurapika.
In the back of your mind,
you sense that something's amiss.
You’re curious as to why Pakunoda
came alone.
If the Troupe were as merciless
as we expected them to be,
this hostage exchange would be impossible.
[Chrollo] You are the one who is cornered.
[Melody] Their rules are ironclad
and their boss accepts them
without question.
But what about the others?
This one appears to be different.
This woman whom you despise
with your whole being
is driven, certainly.
But by the very same motive
that drives you.
She wishes to save her boss...
to save her friend.
You do realize this, don’t you?
Now, return to your companions
and inform them of the exchange.
I want you to bring the hostages
to Lingon Airport before midnight tonight.
Come alone and tell no one
where you're going.
I understand. I will do what you ask.
Take me back to the airport.
You haven't asked any questions.
You know who I am. You must by now.
Aren't you worried?
You don't find this deal unreasonable?
Do you actually believe
I'll return your leader?
-I do.
-[Kurapika gasps]
If you really wanted to deceive me,
you wouldn’t have asked me
those questions.
[thunder crashing]
Does he really expect us
to simply accept those conditions?
Tell us where he is, Paku.
We'll kill the kids and go deal
with the chain user.
You’re insisting?
Damn right I am.
If you don’t tell us,
then you’re not leaving.
I refuse to tell you anything,
and I’m taking the kids alone,
end of story.
Don't interfere.
Screw that. If anyone is interfering,
it’s you!
Go ahead, Pakunoda.
We can stop them, so don't worry.
Stop us? How insulting.
[Phinks] You’re serious, aren’t you?
I don’t get it.
Have you all lost your damn minds?
[Feitan] I think the chain user got
to them before we arrived.
They're probably under his control.
We're wasting time.
I'll make them talk.
[Gon] You really don't get it?
You don't understand why Pakunoda
wants to leave
without telling you anything?
And you don’t understand
why Machi would wanna stop you?
You think it’s because
they’re being manipulated?
It’s ‘cause they wanna rescue your boss!
What else would it be?
They wanna save their friend from danger.
Don’t you understand that?
Shut up, pipsqueak!
You're just desperate to leave!
[Gon grunting]
I’m not saying it to save myself.
Take it back!
[Killua] Man...
[chains breaking]
Take it back?
Come over here and make me.
I’ll rip your head off
the second you take a step.
Then I won’t! You think I’m that stupid?
Kurapika isn't like you.
No matter how much he hates someone,
he would never lose control
and kill them out of anger!
He’s not a murderer!
And you better believe
if Kurapika makes a promise,
then he’s gonna keep his word,
no matter what happens.
Doubt me? Ask Pakunoda.
She’s met him. She knows!
If you just do what he says,
he will return your boss!
[Phinks] All right kid, that's enough.
I’m starting to get real sick
of your crap!
[Franklin] Knock it off!
Just let Pakunoda go.
[Phinks]
What, you're siding with them now?
Hey, Shal, what do you think
our worst-case scenario would be?
Hmm, that the Boss is already dead
and Paku and the rest
are being controlled.
That we won’t be able
to locate the chain user
and the two kids find a way to escape.
[Franklin] You've got it all wrong.
The worst-case scenario is that we all die
and the Spider perishes.
What you’re talking about
would be pretty pleasant by comparison.
Am I wrong?
No, you're right.
Whatever your reasoning,
you’re relying way too much on the boss.
And if the Phantom Troupe falls apart
as a result,
that’d be more of a betrayal
than anything else.
Keep bickering like this
and it might just happen.
So calm down and let them have their way.
Pakunoda can take the kids.
If the boss doesn't return,
we’ll kill the members
who are being controlled
and start rebuilding the spider.
It's really that simple.
[Machi]
I'm fine with that if it'll satisfy you.
Though I’m not being controlled
and killing me won’t be easy.
[scoffs]
[phone ringing]
-Yeah, hello--
-[Kurapika] Put the hostages on the phone.
[Shalnark] Don't break it!
[Kurapika] Are you okay?
Are they there?
Yeah, they're all right here.
[Shalnark] Hey!
Look, we're following your orders.
[Franklin] Aren't you going
to go after them?
I mean, the chain user can’t monitor
our location now.
[Phinks] Shut up.
If I tried to follow them,
you would just stop me, right?
I’ll just wait here for the time being.
And if the Boss doesn’t come back
for whatever reason,
I guess I’ll kill you, too.
[Franklin] As you wish.
[Kurapika] Board the airship.
The pilot knows where to go.
[Melody]
Just the three of them, as promised.
[Kurapika] We can't be sure yet.
So stay on high alert.
There's someone over there.
[phone ringing]
It's him! Hisoka!
[Hisoka] Hey.
What are you doing here?
Did you sneak out?
No need for concern.
I left a double behind.
[Illumi] Make it quick. Without needles,
my face will revert in four to five hours.
[Kurapika] What are you up to?
[Hisoka] Allow me to board the airship
with them.
If you refuse, I'll kill Gon and Killua.
[Kurapika] Bastard.
[Hisoka] I’m only kidding.
I would never be so wasteful.
My target is Chrollo and Chrollo alone.
And I’ll gladly get off the airship
as soon as he is released.
All I want is to fight him.
Nothing more, I promise.
[phone ringing]
[Kurapika] Killua, place the phone
next to your heart.
It’s fine. There’s nothing wrong with him.
Okay. Begin the exchange!
[Kurapika] If you make contact
with a Troupe member, you die.
Now you'll know the pain...
of losing your home.
[Hisoka] I've waited a long time
for this moment.
Come on. Let's fight.
I won’t be needing this anymore.
Now this won’t be considered infighting.
So there’s no need to hold back.
[chuckles] We can talk
because you aren't a Troupe member.
I can't fight you.
Or rather, I’m simply not worth
the trouble.
Because, you see,
he stabbed his Judgment Chain
directly into my heart.
I can't use Nen anymore.
[wind whistling]
It appears that we can leave now.
I see.
[Leorio] Hisoka returned to the airship
without fighting at all.
[Kurapika] The leader probably told him
about my chains
once he realized he wasn’t a member.
But I’m not surprised.
Fighting someone who can’t use Nen
wouldn’t be of much interest to Hisoka.
So wait, he wasn't a Troupe member?
No.
[Pakunoda] How did you sneak out?
[Hisoka]
I have a friend who's good with disguises.
There’s no need to worry.
I no longer have any reason
to kill Chrollo.
I have no interest in broken toys.
“Slip out when it pleases you.”
One more thing.
My real fortune mentioned something.
That I would have a date
with the boss on Tuesday.
It also said that by the time I left,
the Troupe’s numbers would be cut in half.
Bit by bit, fate seems to be changing.
[Kurapika]
I’m sorry for exposing you to danger.
You used your chains on the boss,
didn’t you?
[Kurapika] Yes, but...
Something tells me
that this isn’t the end.
[cat meows]
Meow.
[Phinks] Where's the boss?
[Pakunoda] He can’t come here.
Huh? You’re kidding. You’d better explain.
And if we don’t like it…
[cracking knuckles]
Yes, I know. But don’t worry.
I can only shoot six bullets at once.
Enough for the founding members.
Feitan, Phinks, Machi, Nobunaga,
Shalnark, Franklin...
Will you trust me,
and accept this completely?
[Machi] Paku, you're not...
Hey! Don’t tell me
you’re being controlled--
Be quiet!
It's Paku. You can trust her.
[Pakunoda] All my memories...
My heart and soul...
I give you everything.
[bullets firing]
[gasping]
Please...
Let me be...
the last.
Paku... [grunts]
[Shizuku] She's dead.
What's going on here?
[Phinks] I’ll explain everything.
[thunder rumbling]
Now we know. She did this because…
[Gon] I sure hope Kurapika's fever
doesn't go down.
[Killua] Yeah.
Hold on. What did you just say?
[Gon] I feel like Kurapika shouldn’t fight
the Phantom Troupe anymore.
[Killua] Huh?
[Gon] When he told me about his abilities,
I thought of something.
If all he had really wanted
was to get revenge,
then he probably would have
taken on different abilities.
[Killua] Think so?
I do. Because If he had only wanted
to kill the Troupe,
he wouldn’t have gone through the trouble
of chaining their hearts. I wouldn't have.
Maybe, if he only had one target.
Instead, he was dealing with all of them.
He couldn’t catch and kill one right away.
He’d need to extract information
about the others.
[Gon] Oh.
[Killua] I think his ability was created
solely for revenge.
I see.
But that was his original objective.
Kurapika's different now.
I'm blessed with good friends.
[Killua] But you've got a point.
He really should stay still
for a little while.
If their boss doesn’t come back,
they’re gonna be even more determined
to find him.
[Gon] Yeah.
[Killua] Either way,
we’re gonna have to be careful
when we go to the auction house.
-So, do you really have a plan?
-[gasps]
Something to help us get our hands
on Greed Island?
'Cause that’s all we have to go on!
Uh, yeah, but it's only a 50-50 chance.
Wait, didn’t you say 70 percent earlier?
I get it. That's pretty clever.
And it might be our only shot.
It’s practical and sound, too.
Yeah! The way I see it,
our odds are 80 percent!
-Really?
-Really. Let's do it.
[Gon] The auction is in Hall B.
[Killua] That's it, over there.
[Gon] Wow!
[both startle]
[both grunting]
What the heck are those guys doing here?
How would I know?
[Phinks] You know, that was cold.
No need for you to run away.
[Killua] Why wouldn't we run?
Yeah, don't worry.
We’re not here to kill you two
or anything.
He’s right. It’s not like we can kill
the chain user now anyway.
[Gon] What? What do you mean?
[Phinks] Well, he used his chains
on the boss, didn’t he?
That means we can’t kill him.
I thought it was the opposite.
[Killua] It’s nice to have someone around
who never shies away
from asking questions.
When you die, it doesn’t mean
your Nen disappears.
Nen that's driven by hatred and regret
can last a long time after death.
And it will direct itself
toward the target of those emotions.
Since the boss can’t use Nen
himself anymore,
he’s all the more vulnerable
to that kind of assault.
Scary, that residual Nen.
That's why we can't kill the chain user.
Am I talking too much?
Fine, then. I won't say another word.
There are Nen users a few, anyway,
who can remove Nen from other people.
[wind whistling]
[Chrollo] Hmm. East it is.
So, as you might’ve guessed,
we’re pretty much done
with the two of you.
The only reason we’re even here
is to enjoy the auction.
The other members decided
to pack up and go home already.
Hold on. How's Miss Pakunoda?
She died, actually.
Oh, I see.
[Pakunoda] I don't get it.
Why don't you run away?
What do you mean by that?
[Pakunoda] With my injuries,
you could escape easily.
And if you did, I would lose my leverage,
and the chain user could kill the boss.
So why not run away?
Aren't you on his side?
Well, we’re his friends!
And we all care about him.
And we don’t want him to turn
into a murderer.
If an exchange will do the job,
that’s what we’ll do.
-[Gon] What's wrong?
-[Killua] Let's go.
[Phinks] Paku...
Paku was very thankful to both of you.
[narrator] Tune in next time,
when the Greed Island arc begins!
[theme music playing]
-[Gon] Coming up, Gon...
-[Killua] And Killua's...
[both] Hunterpedia!
-I'm Gon!
-I'm Killua!
[both] And this is our Hunterpedia!
Today, we're introducing Chrollo!
He's a Specialist and the boss
of the Phantom Troupe!
He can steal other people's powers
for himself with his Skill Hunter!
As long as certain conditions are met.
Huh. East it is.
[Gon] Next time: "Bid x and x Haste."
[Gon] A bid in haste makes a whole lot
of waste. Hey!
[Killua] And a bad aftertaste.